Divine Ede

United Kingdom

divine.ede@yahoo.com

07417526408

linkedin.com/in/divineede

Summary

Currently studying my MSC in computer science at University of York. I am passionate about technology and have over 5 years professional working experience in Graphic design, now looking to develop a new and full filling career in tech.

Experience

Freelance Web Designer

Just Divine Graphics

Jul 2020 - Present (3 years 8 months)

liaising with clients to determine their requirements, timescale and budget.

managing client proposals from typesetting through to graphic design, print and production.

working with clients' ideas and managing their expectations.

developing concepts, graphics and layouts, including making decisions about fonts, images, readability and readers' needs.

determining size and arrangement of copy and illustrative material, as well as font style and size. preparing rough drafts of material based on an agreed brief.

keeping clients up to date, listening to and acting on feedback, and explaining the rationale behind graphic design decisions.

reviewing final layouts and suggesting improvements if required.

keeping up to date with design and software trends.

liaising with external printers or production teams to ensure deadlines are met and material is printed or presented to the highest quality.



Graphic Designer

Mintec

Jul 2018 - Oct 2020 (2 years 4 months)

Duties & responsibilities include

Developing design briefs that suit the client's purpose, coming up with creatives to produce new ideas and concepts and developing interactive design.

Supporting the senior designer to design communications materials such as social media posts, logos and helped to develop the company's styleguide and brand.

Worked with a range of internal and external stakeholders and was able to develop good working relationships. I worked successfully as part of the marketing team, and was also able to work on my own initiative.

I also had to work with design software in Adobe Creative Suite (Macintosh) and creating templates and powerpoint decks in Microsoft Office. I also worked to create large print designs for exhibitions and posters and produced print

creating ready artwork and also used Adobe AfterEffect to create motion graphics. Using innovation to redefine a design brief within time and cost constraints. I also got to work on real design projects such as Infographics, poster, digital eBooks, print design, landing page designs and helped to finalise ideas and concepts to clients or account managers. I also develop my eye for detail to proofread creatives for accurate and high-quality work. I also worked with the marketing team and share ideas to develop the team.

Junior Web Designer

Dynamis

Sep 2017 - May 2018 (9 months)

Responsibilities included:

Work with the Senior Web Designer to create stunning website templates and mock-ups for a host of clients, ensuring each design meets the brief

Play a key role in the design lifecycle, from brief through to design and release/implementation

Ensure all designs work across all browsers and on all devices

Modify templates to reflect the tone and style of the client/brand

Ensure all designs produced deliver great user experience

MABOX Junior Graphic/Creative artworker

Mabox

Jun 2016 - Aug 2017 (1 year 3 months)

My responsibilities include:

Supporting the senior designer in the day-to-day agency needs in the studio.

Working across print & digital on a broad cross-section of brands from a marketing angle.

Managing multiple projects at once, switching between clients and internal work and different outputs easily.

Ensuring that all processes are followed and take responsibility for all client brand guidelines.

Working across amendments, prepare artwork for print or build, proof and check materials and manage my workload efficiently.

🕊 Digital & Graphic Design Intern

TotallyMoney

Oct 2015 - Dec 2015 (3 months)

Job Responsibilities Include:

- Created designs for marketing collaterals
- Developing concepts, graphics and layouts
- Created Illustrations, and social media campaigns
- · Created wireframes and mockup for new credit card landing page

Graphic Design Intern

Barnardo's

Jun 2013 - Jan 2014 (8 months)

My responsibilities included helping to deliver design solutions, from visual through to hi-resolution digital artwork for a range of promotional marketing material including project literature, information leaflets, internal communications, stationery items and fundraising support materials.

Provide design support to creative team, including:

- making corrections to InDesign files, proofreading
- working closely with other designers and the production manager
- manipulating images
- putting together concept mock-ups for presentation
- contributing ideas to creative concept development and discussions
- talking to clients on the telephone and email to ask them about design briefs
- working towards style guides and branding specifications
- work shadowing the web development manager

Media and Public Relation Intern

News4Media

Aug 2013 - Aug 2013 (1 month)

My role was to work with the Communication Channel for the Company promoting news for media professionals such as Journalists, Bloggers, Brands and PRs, editing blogs and using range of Marketing and Social Media tools including Twitter networking and LinkedIn.

Education



Time University of York

Master of Science - MS, Computer Science 2022 - 2024



Loughborough University

BA Honours Graphic Communication, Graphic Design

Sep 2012 - Jun 2015

The course focuses on teaching practical and creative skills in traditional and new, analogue, and digital media, as well as an understanding of relevant social, cultural, economic, ethical, and sustainable contexts. Graphic Design at Loughborough is a highly competitive course.

Modules include:

Core ideas and concepts of graphic design practice Typography and writing systems Digital competencies and production skills

Applied image-making methods and procedures Critical and written skills in design Branding, storytelling and graphic systems

Visualisation techniques, methods and rationales Narrative and sequential graphic design practices Practical and theoretical introduction to social design Collaborative and participatory design processes Interrelationships of audience and environments Guided design research study

Kensington and Chelsea College

BTEC Foundation Diploma in Art and Design, Graphic Design Jan 2011 - Jun 2012

Palmers' Sixth Form College

AS and A levels, Mathematics, Graphic Design, English Literature 2009 - 2011

Licenses & Certifications

Google UX Design Professional Certificate - Coursera

Level 3 Principles in Digital Marketing and Research - Back2Work Complete Training



Skills

Adobe Design Programs • WordPress • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Motion Graphics • Adobe Illustrator • Adobe InDesign • Adobe Photoshop • HTML • JavaScript • Graphic Design

Honors & Awards

Graphic Communications - Loughborough University Jul 2015